Cristian Butiri

+40746547487 | butiri.cristian@gmail.com | Cluj-Napoca, Județul Cluj

Summary

Full-Stack Software Engineer with more than 6 years of experience in the field. I'm interested in back-end technologies such as Ruby on Rails, Node.js or Go but I also enjoy creating user-friendly interfaces, having more than 4 years of experience in React. For more details and to check out recommendations please go ahead and visit my personal website here: https://www.cristianbutiri.com/

Experience

Freeleance via Toptal @&Open Senior Software Engineer | 09/2022 - 01/2023

I was responsible with improving the experience of Customer Support Managers by adding new features such as:

- Built an administrative page for campaigns removing 80% of the software engineers' support work related to this area of the project
- Helped with the integration of a new client by customizing 2 new themes for their React front-end and for their Slim email templates
- Surfaced to the UI errors coming from fulfiller integrations enabling CSM's to solve their issues independently and removing another 20% of engineers' needed support

Freelance via Toptal @Influence Mobile Senior Software Engineer | 02/2021 - 08/2022

- Designed and developed a new web application from the ground up, using Ruby on Rails 6 and React 17+, to manage various mobile games' and apps' campaigns and offers for more than 100 clients
- Integrated the new app with existing systems by using AWS's SQS to keep both systems in sync while handling 1000+ messages per day
- Created a real-time notification system by using web sockets to inform users of specific messages processed through the SQS gueue to improve user experience from a score of 7.3 to 8.6
- Handled production deployments and maintenance of the web app while keeping a test coverage above 90%
- Collaborated closely with the PM and the clients by having weekly and daily meetings to establish new features and find solutions for existing issues

Freelance via Toptal @Spaceback Senior Software Engineer | 02/2021 - 06/2021

- Improved error tracking and the time required for debugging by 80%, by adding new relevant details to the context of the errors reported
- Refactored 7 classes used to parse webpages by extracting the common functionality into a superclass and using inheritance and composition
- Adapted 1 page written in Stimulus to include React Components in order to improve code readability and page loading times

Take Off Labs | Cluj-Napoca, Cluj County Senior Software Engineer | 01/2019 - 03/2021

- Added 10+ endpoints to a REST API used by iOS and Android mobile apps, to allow golf players to register for events and track scores
- Converted a classic HAML Ruby page to React components and improved the response times from about 30 seconds to 3 seconds per request using caching, pagination, and other optimization methods
- Engineered an integration system with a different provider to synchronize more than 10000 golf players' data, both on a daily basis as well as whenever an SSO sign-in occurred
- Generated a new Player Dashboard using React and Ruby on Rails accessed by 1000+ users daily
- Extended the member profile page with 2 new pages loaded asynchronously through AJAX requests
- Created 1 background job to handle multi-threaded requests to an external API and process the results

Accesa | Cluj-Napoca, Cluj County Junior Java Developer | 06/2017 - 02/2019

 Participated in creating an internal management tool for the HR department to track the interview processes for new internship candidates, by utilizing Java 8, Angular 2, PostgreSQL, and CQRS as an architecture

- Contributed to a B2B eCommerce platform for tracking orders to and from multiple physical stores, using Java 8 and Angular 2
- Experienced working in the Hybris ecosystem through an application built for training purposes in less than 6 weeks

Personal Projects

Draw Cells

- Collaborated with a Phd from Oxford University to launch a web app that allows users to easily create different types of animations for scientific presentations in less than 1 hour.
- Selected a tech stack including React 17, Typescript, Material UI 5, Firebase, Konva, React-Spring and many more React libraries.

Flourish

- Flourish was created as a replacement for a company's service that used to manage campaigns and offers for mobile games and apps. The project was completely designed and built by me to help the company I was working for with their ongoing business
- The project was created using the latest technologies such as Rails 6 and React 17+ with Material UI 5 and deployed on AWS Services. AWS SQS was also used to keep in sync the legacy project with the new app. The DBMS used was PostgreSQL

eCommerce API

- The project was created during Toptal's NodeJS Accelerator and consisted of 2 services: 1 for user auth and management and 1 for product management
- The tech stack consisted of Node.JS with Express and Nest, while Auth0 was used as an authentication server. For
 this project I also had the chance to work again and experiment more with MongoDB and its Node library Mongoose.

Skills

React, Ruby on Rails, Python, Node.js, JavaScript, Typescript, SQL, Express.js

Education

Babes-Bolyai University of Cluj-Napoca | Cluj-Napoca, Cluj County Computer Science | 07/2018

Bachelor's degree in Computer Science, graduated with a grade of 9.05/10